A Guide to the Alexandria Gazette Ledgers, 1833-1866
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Gazette Ledgers 1833-1866
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
26
5 boxes (6.6 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Alternative Form Available
A full run of the Alexandria Gazette is available on microfilm; 1833-1866 is found on reels 53-112.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Alexandria Gazette was under the editorship of Edgar Snowden, Sr. from 1831-1875. While under his leadership the Gazette served as Snowden's showcase for political and civic views. In addition to the Gazette, Snowden ran a printing office from out of the Gazette's offices.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the accounts ledgers of the Alexandria Gazette from 1833-1866. Advertisers' names, charges, and dates run are recorded in the advertisement ledgers. Other account books record printing charges, as well as petty advertising accounts. Additionally, two route books from 1859 are available.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into the following series: 1) Financial Records (1833-1866) - Chrolological by year. 2) Miscellaneous (1859).
Index Terms
Snowden, Edgar, 1810-1875; Alexandria Gazette; Newspaper Publishing - Alexandria, Va.; Alexandria, Va. - Newspapers
Contents List
- Financial Records, 1833-1866.
  - Advertisement book, 1833-1840. (Box-folder 26A:1)
  - Advertisement book, 1833-1840, enclosures. (Box-folder 26A:2)
  - Advertisement book, 1840-1844. (Box-folder 26A:3)
  - Advertisement book, 1848-1851. (Box-folder 26A:4)
  - Accounts ledger, 1833-1861. (Box-folder 26B:1)
  - Accounts ledger, 1833-1861, enclosures. (Box-folder 26B:2)
  - Check register, 1839-1854. (Box-folder 26B:3)
  - Accounts ledger, 1854-1866. (Box-folder 26C:1)
  - Accounts ledger, 1854-1866, enclosures. (Box-folder 26C:2)
  - Accounts ledger, index, 1854-1866. (Box-folder 26C:3)
  - Petty ledger, 1855-1861. (Box-folder 26D:1)
  - Petty ledger, 1855-1861, clippings. (Box-folder 26D:2)
  - Petty ledger, 1855-1861, enclosures. (Box-folder 26D:3)
  - Day book, 1855-1856. (Box-folder 26D:4)
  - Day book, 1855-1856, enclosures. (Box-folder 26D:5)
  - Day book, 1855-1856, clippings. (Box-folder 26D:6)
  - Accounts ledger, 1858-1862. (Box-folder 26E:1)
- Miscellaneous, 1859.
  - Route books, 1859, (2). (Box-folder 26A:5)